bangor.ac.uk 2015-05-31

# The University

## Official Web Pages

Official University pages have a "base" URL in one of the following formats:

  * http://www.bangor.ac.uk/directoryname/ e.g. <http://www.bangor.ac.uk/courses>
  * http://sitename.bangor.ac.uk/ eg. <http://barheadedgoose.bangor.ac.uk/>

## Website Privacy Policy and Data Protection

The University is a Registered Data Controller as defined by the Data Protection Act 1998. Any personal details collected through this web site and provided by you will be processed in accordance with the Act, and will only be used for the purpose or purposes stated on the relevant page.

You may also wish to consult our;

  * Privacy Policy (Website)

## Website Privacy and cookies

On most of the pages on our official websites we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out the number of visitors to the various parts of the University's websites. We collect this information in a way that does not identify anyone. We make no attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. 

We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will tell you about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it. An example of this would be where we use a form to allow you to request a prospectus or other such information.

### Use of cookies by the Bangor University website

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. **By using our website(s) you are agreeing that we can place cookies on your device.** If you do not wish us to store any cookies during your visit please see the 'rejecting and disabling cookies via your browser settings' section of this page and the links to specific cookies that can be rejected. Please note however that this may have a significant impact on your experience.

The table below explains the sitewide cookies we use and why. 

**Cookie Name** | **Purpose** | **More Information**  
---|---|---  
__utma | A Google Analytics cookie. These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. This cookie has a lifespan of 2 years from set/update. | 

**How to reject or delete this cookie**

To find out more about Google Analytics privacy policies or to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit:   
<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

**By using our website(s) you are agreeing that we can place this cookie on your device.**  
  
__utmc | A Google Analytics cookie. These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. This cookie is no longer used by the ga.js tracking code to determine session status and so a value is not set. | 

**How to reject or delete this cookie**

To find out more about Google Analytics privacy policies or to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit:   
<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

**By using our website(s) you are agreeing that we can place this cookie on your device.**  
  
__utmb | A Google Analytics cookie. These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. 30 minutes from set/update. | 

**How to reject or delete this cookie**

To find out more about Google Analytics privacy policies or to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit:   
<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

**By using our website(s) you are agreeing that we can place this cookie on your device.**  
  
__utmv | A Google Analytics cookie. These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. This cookies has a lifespan of 2 years from set/update, however we do not always use Google Analytics in a way that sets this cookie. | 

**How to reject or delete this cookie**

To find out more about Google Analytics privacy policies or to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit:   
<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

**By using our website(s) you are agreeing that we can place this cookie on your device.**  
  
__utmz | A Google Analytics cookie. These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. This cookies has a lifespan of 6 months from set/update. | 

**How to reject or delete this cookie**

To find out more about Google Analytics privacy policies or to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit:   
<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

**By using our website(s) you are agreeing that we can place this cookie on your device.**  
  
PHPSESSID | Session cookie essential to the operation of some parts of the website. Removed when you close you browser. No personal information is stored. | Where used these cookies are required for our site to function properly.  
  
prefer-language | Session cookie used to store your language preference for the site. Essential for site use. Removed when you close you browser. No personal information is stored. | Where used these cookies are required for our site to function properly.  
WPM%5FStore | Session cookie - only used within shop.bangor.ac.uk to allow shopping cart to function. No personal information is stored. | Where used these cookies are required for our site to function properly.  
WPM%5FStore%5FSession | Session cookie - only used within shop.bangor.ac.uk to allow shopping cart to function. No personal information is stored. | Where used these cookies are required for our site to function properly.  
ASPSESSIONIDSARCSBRA | Session cookie - only used within shop.bangor.ac.uk to allow shopping cart to function. No personal information is stored. | Where used these cookies are required for our site to function properly.  
CompanyID | Session cookie - only used within shop.bangor.ac.uk to allow shopping cart to function. No personal information is stored. | Where used these cookies are required for our site to function properly.  
Site_Val | Session cookie - only used within payment gateway at shop.bangor.ac.uk to allow shopping cart to function. No personal information is stored. | Where used these cookies are required for our site to function properly.  
ASPSESSIONID | Session cookie - only used within payment gateway at shop.bangor.ac.uk to allow shopping cart to function. No personal information is stored. | Where used these cookies are required for our site to function properly.  
fontSize | This cookie is used in some pages to store your fontSize preference. No personal information is stored. This cookie is removed when you close you browser. | Where used these cookies are required for that part of our site to function properly.  
pageStyle_BUACCESSCENTRE | This cookie is used in some pages to store your page style preference. No personal information is stored. This cookie is removed when you close you browser. | Where used these cookies are required for that part of our site to function properly.  
csrftoken | Used on our mobile site as part of the site functionality. No personal information is stored. This cookie has a 12 month lifespan. | Where used these cookies are required for that part of our site to function properly.  
django_language | Used on our mobile site as part of the site functionality, storing your language preference. No personal information is stored. This cookie is removed when you close you browser. | Where used these cookies are required for that part of our site to function properly.  
sessionid | Used on our mobile site as part of the site functionality. No personal information is stored. This cookie has a 31 day lifespan. | Where used these cookies are required for that part of our site to function properly.  
  
### Google Analytics cookies

We use **Google Analytics** to help analyse use of our website. This analytical tool uses cookies to collect standard web log information and visitor behaviour information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Bangor website (including your IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to evaluate visitors' use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity for the University. 

To find out more about Google Analytics, visit: [www.google.co.uk/analytics](http://www.google.co.uk/analytics).

If you wish to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, visit: [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

### Local Shared Objects (Flash Cookies)

We may make occasional and limited use of the Adobe Flash Player to deliver services. To improve user experience, Local Shared Objects - or Flash Cookies as they are commonly known - are employed to provide some features. Flash Cookies are stored on a user's terminal much the same as cookies are, however it is not possible to manage them at browser level in the same way.

The Adobe website provides comprehensive information on how to delete or disable Flash cookies either for a specific domain like bangor.ac.uk or for all websites - see <http://www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security> for details. Please be aware that restricting the use of Flash Cookies may affect the features available to you for Flash based applications. 

### Cookies set for embedded social web content

To support our information provision and engagement, we sometimes embed photos and video content from websites such as YouTube and Flickr. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Flickr, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. We do not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third party websites for more information about these.

Cookies of this nature on our websites include:

 SERVICE |  COOKIE NAME  
---|---  
 .facebook.com |  datr  
 .facebook.com |  lsd  
 .facebook.com |  lu  
 .facebook.com |  gz  
  |    
 Flickr |  localization  
 Flickr |  B  
  |    
 twitter.com |  guest_id  
 api.twitter.com |  guest_id  
 twitter.com |  _twitter_sess  
 api.twitter.com |  original_referer  
  
  |    
 .youtube.com |  VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  
 .youtube.com |  PREF  
 .youtube.com |  GEO  
 .s.youtube.com |  PREF  
  
Some of our websites also carry embedded 'share' buttons to enable users of the site to easily share articles with their peers through a number of popular social networks. These sites may set a cookie when you are also logged in to or otherwise using their service. 

### YouTube cookies - set using Privacy Enhanced Mode

On some pages we embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit [YouTube's embedding videos information page](http://www.google.com/support/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=171780 "External link").

### S7 'Add This' cookies

On some of our pages we provide our users with a tool from AddThis <http://www.addthis.com/> . This service allows users to share our page content with other people via many different social networking sites. By default this service uses cookies, however we have disabled the use of cookies for AddThis on most of our pages following the information provided by the AddThis support team. The cookie set by the AddThis service is called '__atuvc'. 

### Accessibility toolbar cookies

On some of our sites we have additional accessibility tools installed. These set cookies called 'fontSize' and 'pageStyle_BUACCESSCENTRE'. These are essential for the operation of those parts of the site and are removed when you close you browser. No personal information is stored by these cookies.

## Blackboard

Blackboard is our Virtual Learning Environment and is used by staff and students at Bangor University. Blackboard uses cookies in order to provide functionality - no personal data is stored and these cookies are removed when you close your browser. These are initialised when you visit the Blackboard login page, which is open to the public, are essential for the operation of those parts of the site, are removed when you close you browser and are as follows;

JSESSIONID | Session cookie - used within blackboard.bangor.ac.uk. No personal information is stored. Removed when you close your browser.  
---|---  
s_session_id | Session cookie - used within blackboard.bangor.ac.uk. No personal information is stored. Removed when you close your browser.  
session_id | Session cookie - used within blackboard.bangor.ac.uk. No personal information is stored. Removed when you close your browser.  
  
## Library Catalogue system

Our Millenium based library catalog system uses cookies to provide functionality. No personal data is stored and these cookies are removed when you close your browser. These are initialised when you visit the Library catalogue system, which is open to the public, are essential for the operation of those parts of the site, and are as follows;

III_EXPT_FILE | Session cookie - used within the library system. No personal information is stored. Removed when you close your browser.  
---|---  
III_SESSION_ID | Session cookie - used within the library system. No personal information is stored. Removed when you close your browser.  
SESSION_SCOPE | Session cookie - used within the library system. No personal information is stored. Removed when you close your browser.  
  
## BangorPortal/Campus Pipeline system

BangorPortal uses cookies to provide functionality. No personal data is stored and these cookies are removed when you close your browser. These are initialised when you visit the BangorPortal system (also known as pipeline.bangor.ac.uk)- the login page of which is open to the public, are essential for the operation of those parts of the site, and are as follows;

JSESSIONID | Session cookie - used within the BangorPortal system. No personal information is stored. Removed when you close your browser.  
---|---  
UserAgentId | Session cookie - used within the BangorPortal system. No personal information is stored. Removed when you close your browser.  
sctSession | Session cookie - used within the BangorPortal system. No personal information is stored. Removed when you close your browser.  
  
## Online gazette

The online gazette system (admint.bangor.ac.uk) set a single session cookie when the home page is visited. This cookie 'ASPSESSIONIDQQGQQHQF' does not store any personal data and is removed when you close your browser. Where used this cookiee is required for our site to function properly.

## Webmail

Our internal email system, Webmail, sets two cookies on its login page - which are used by Webmail to provide functionality once users have logged in. These are 'Horde' and 'auth_key'. These cookies do not store any personal data and they are removed when you close your browser. Where used this cookie is required for our site to function properly.

## Inside.Bangor

This internal system sets Googe Tracking cookies and two other cookies on its publicly visible homepage. These additional two cookies are a PHP session variable to manage login and identification. It's name is randomly generated but starts with 'SESS' and is set to the domain 'inside.bangor.ac.uk'. The second additional cookie is 'has_js' which is used to provide inside.bangor with information about your browsers ability to use Javascript. Neither of these two cookies store any personal data and they are removed when you close your browser. Where used this cookiee is required for our site to function properly.

## Pontio.co.uk

In addition to the Google Analytics cookies outlined above the Pontio site uses two cookies to store language preference. The 'int_pontio_language_bu' has a 12 month lifespan, the 'prefer-language' cookie is a session cookie and is removed when you close your browser. No personal data is stored in either of these cookies.

## Rejecting and disabling cookies via your browser settings

You can choose not to accept cookies and still use the Bangor University web site, but some essential functionality may be lost. For example, user preferences will not be retained if cookies are disabled, and some parts of the site may not function as intended.

The documentation for your web browser will provide you with instructions on how to [disable cookies you could visit this About Cookies webpage](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1).. 

Alternatively please visit this site <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/> for further information.

## Other cookies on our public websites

As functionality and new services are added/integrated into our website we may need to use additional cookies. This page of our site will be updated as a when we make use of new cookies or catgories of cookies. If you wish to inform us about a cookie then please do [contact us](mailto:s.foster@bangor.ac.uk).

## Personal Staff and Student web pages

Personal web pages on University servers are distinguished by the use of the tilde character (~) in the URL, usually followed by the login name of the individual responsible for the pages e.g. 

http://pages.bangor.ac.uk/~loginname

Personal web pages are hosted at <http://pages.bangor.ac.uk/>.

Personal staff, student and other non-BU templated web pages remain the **sole responsibility of the page author** , even when linked to official pages on the University web site. The University shall not be liable for the content or presentation of such pages.

**If you have web pages hosted on pages.bangor.ac.uk** then you should [consult this article on the JISC Legal website](http://www.jisclegal.ac.uk/ManageContent/ViewDetail/ID/2051/What-Does-the-New-Cookie-Legislation-Require-us-to-do.aspx). Please [contact the ITS HelpDesk for further guidance](http://www.bangor.ac.uk/itservices/help/index.php.en) as we will be happy to help you work towards compliance.

## Other websites hosted at Bangor University

A number of other websites are hosted at the University. These include sites for research projects, organisations and collaborative activites. 

These web pages remain the **sole responsibility of the page or site author/owner** , even when linked to official pages on the University web site. The University shall not be liable for the content or presentation of such pages.

**If you are responsible for any web based content hosted at the University** , and your site does not use the University template system, then you must ensure that your site is compliant with appropriate legislation.

For information regarding your responsibilities with regards website privacy and cookies please [consult this article on the JISC Legal website](http://www.jisclegal.ac.uk/ManageContent/ViewDetail/ID/2051/What-Does-the-New-Cookie-Legislation-Require-us-to-do.aspx) and [contact the ITS HelpDesk for further guidance](http://www.bangor.ac.uk/itservices/help/index.php.en) as we will be happy to help you work towards compliance.
